<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<preopData>
<pageHeader1>Breast Biopsy</pageHeader1>
<pageHeader2>Incisional</pageHeader2>
<pageTitle>PreOp.com Breast Biopsy - Incisional</pageTitle>
<directory templateDir="/asp" image="/image" videoMedia="/media" audioMedia="/media" slideimage="/image" />
<prodId>332</prodId>
<siteId>preop</siteId>
<phdivision></phdivision>
<!--
Input Procedure Name

PROCEDURE INFO:
ANESTESIA = 1
BEFORE = 1
RECOVERY = 1

Do a 'Find & Replace All' with the new procedure number

//-->


<!-- ADD POSTCARE SPECIFIC TASKS //-->
<prodRelation prodId="411" sexId="shemale" siteId="postcare">Hand Washing</prodRelation>
<prodRelation prodId="412" sexId="shemale" siteId="postcare">Gloving</prodRelation>
<prodRelation prodId="420" sexId="shemale" siteId="postcare">Wound Care</prodRelation>



<navElement secId="2" template="/template1.asp">Your Body</navElement>
<navElement secId="3" template="/template1.asp">Alternatives</navElement>
<navElement secId="4" template="/template1.asp">Medical Record</navElement>
<navElement secId="5" template="/template1.asp">Anesthesia</navElement>
<navElement secId="6" template="/template1.asp">Before Surgery</navElement>
<navElement secId="7" template="/template1.asp">Your Procedure</navElement>
<navElement secId="8" template="/template1.asp">Recovery</navElement>


<!--
for bold text use:
&lt;b&gt; B &lt;/b&gt;
equals <b> B </b>

for paragraphs text use:
&lt;p&gt; all your text &lt;/p&gt;
equals <p> all your text </p>

for bullets text use:
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; all your text &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
equals <ul> <li> all your text </li> </ul> 

//-->



<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (2) YOUR BODY //-->

<audioImage secId="2" image="/000/preop/host_audio2.gif" audioMapQT="/332/audio_2body_332.mov"  audioMapWM="/332/audio_2body_332.wma"/>

<videoImage secId="2" spotId="1" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_2body1_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_2body1_332.wmv"/>
<videoImage secId="2" spotId="4" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_2body2_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_2body2_332.wmv"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->


<topHtml secId="2" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;B&lt;/B&gt;efore we talk about treatment, let's start with a discussion about the human body and about your medical condition.
&lt;p&gt; Your doctor has recommended that you undergo a breast biopsy procedure - or lumpectomy. But what does that actually mean? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Biopsy is a general term which simply means "the removal of tissue for microscopic examination." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Your doctor intends to remove tissue from the breast - not because you're necessarily ill - but because breast biopsy is a very accurate method for analyzing breast tissue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Because it provides such accurate diagnostic information, breast biopsy is an important diagnostic tool in the fight against breast cancer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<botHtml secId="2">&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In order to learn more about the nature of the lump in your breast your doctor would like to surgically remove it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Most likely, you're feeling some anxiety about this procedure, which is perfectly understandable. You should realize that it's natural to feel apprehensive about any kind of biopsy. In some cases, a woman will choose not to have a biopsy simply out of fear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But ignoring a lump in your breast won't make it go away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you're feeling anxious, try to remember that the purpose of a biopsy is simply to find out what is going on in your body - so that if you do have a problem, it can be diagnosed and treated as quickly as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you should decide not to allow your doctor to perform the biopsy, you'll be leaving yourself at risk for medical problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If the suspicious tissue in your breast is benign, most likely you'll suffer few if any complications. However, if it is cancerous, and it is allowed to grow unchecked - you might be putting your own life at risk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The bottom line - trust that your doctor is recommending this procedure for your benefit and above all don't be afraid to ask questions raised by this video and to talk openly about your concerns. &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>

<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="1" slideimage="/332/332-2-01b.gif" image="/332/332-2-01.gif">In your case, you have lump or thickening in your breast.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="2" slideimage="/332/332-2-02b.gif" image="/332/332-2-02.gif">It was felt by you or your doctor during a routine breast exam or discovered following a mammogram. Let's take a moment to look at the reasons why lumps form in breast tissue.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="3" slideimage="/332/332-2-03b.gif" image="/332/332-2-03.gif">The breast is made of layers of skin, fat and breast tissue - all of which overlay the pectoralis muscle. Breast tissue itself is made up of a network of tiny-milk carrying ducts and there are three ways in which a lump can form among them.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="4" slideimage="/332/332-2-04b.gif" image="/332/332-2-04.gif">Most women experience periodic changes to their breasts. Cysts are some of the most common kinds of tissues that can grow large enough to be felt and to cause tenderness. Cysts often grow and then shrink without any medical intervention.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="5" slideimage="/332/332-2-05b.gif" image="/332/332-2-05.gif">A second kind of lump is caused by changes in breast tissue triggered by the growth of a cyst. Even after the cyst itself has gone away, it can leave fibrous tissue behind. This scar tissue can often be large enough to be felt.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="6" slideimage="/332/332-2-06b.gif" image="/332/332-2-06.gif">The third kind of growth is a tumor. Tumors can be either benign or cancerous and it is concern about this type of growth that has lead your doctor to recommend breast biopsy.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="2" spotId="7" slideimage="/332/332-2-07b.gif" image="/332/332-2-07.gif">Sometimes you will have breast changes that can not be felt by physical examination alone; but may be seen on a mammogram.</procedureInfo>




<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (3) ALTERNATIVES //-->

<audioImage secId="3" image="/000/preop/host_audio3.gif" audioMapQT="/332/audio_3alt_332.mov"  audioMapWM="/332/audio_3alt_332.wma"/>

<videoImage secId="x" spotId="x" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_3alt1_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_3alt1_332.wmv"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<topHtml secId="3" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;Y&lt;/B&gt;our doctor understands that all medical care benefits from close collaboration between physician and patient -- so be sure to review, with your doctor, all risks and alternatives and make sure you understand the reasons behind the recommendation for this particular procedure.
&lt;p&gt; Now let's talk in detail about the procedure your doctor has recommended. That particular recommendation was based on a number of factors: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medviolet"&gt;the state of your health, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medviolet"&gt; the severity of your condition, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medviolet"&gt; an assessment of alternative treatments or procedures and finally, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medviolet"&gt; the risks associated with doing nothing at all. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And remember, the final decision is up to you. No one can force you to undergo a surgical procedure against your will. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; There are a number of methods of performing breast biopsy. The choice between them is generally made according to the location and size of the lump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<botHtml secId="3">&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Now I'd like to introduce you to another important member of the medical team -- the nurse.  &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>

<procedureInfo secId="3" spotId="1" slideimage="/332/332-3-01b.gif" image="/332/332-3-01.gif">In this video, we will focus only on simple excision biopsy - which is the attempt to surgically remove the entire lump for laboratory analysis.</procedureInfo>




<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (4) MEDICAL RECORD //-->

<audioImage secId="4" image="/000/preop/host_audio4.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_4med.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_4med.wma"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->


<topHtml secId="4" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;O&lt;/B&gt;ver the course of the procedure, you'll be under the care of one or more nurses. Our job is to provide for your care and comfort - before, during and after surgery.
&lt;p&gt; On the day of surgery, it's important that you tell us how you're feeling. And we certainly want you and your family to feel completely free to ask us any questions at any time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Before the operation, your doctors will examine your medical history as well as your current physical condition. This is an important step because the results of that exam will help your medical team to make decisions about your care. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; So remember, it is very important that you give your doctor your complete medical history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Be sure to remember to &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; report previous illnesses, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; previous surgeries, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; whether or not you smoke &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; and current illnesses or medical problems. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And if you're currently taking any medications &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; prescription or over-the-counter, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; or if you have any known allergies &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; to medications or other substances, &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; make sure to tell your doctor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Some of the most common questions patients ask their doctors are about anesthesia. So I'd like to introduce you to the anesthesiologist. &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<botHtml secId="x"></botHtml>




<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (5) ANESTHESIA //-->

<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio5.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_5ana0.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_5ana0.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="5" image="/000/preop/host_audio5.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_5ana1.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_5ana1.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio5.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_5ana2.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_5ana2.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio5.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_5ana3.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_5ana3.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio5.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_5ana4.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_5ana4.wma"/>

<videoImage secId="5" spotId="1" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/000/video_5ana1.mov" videoMapWM="/000/video_5ana1.wmv"/>
<videoImage secId="5" spotId="3" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/000/video_5ana2.mov" videoMapWM="/000/video_5ana2.wmv"/>
<videoImage secId="x" spotId="x" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/000/video_5ana3.mov" videoMapWM="/000/video_5ana3.wmv"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->


<!-- ANA Header ALL //-->
<topHtml secId="5" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;M&lt;/B&gt;ost people understand that anesthesia is used to block the perception of pain - but anesthesia plays another, equally important role as well. Let me explain.
&lt;p&gt; Anesthesia allows your surgical team to control - and to monitor - a wide range of natural physiological reflexes. As you know, all surgery involves cutting small amounts of skin or other tissue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Your mind certainly knows the difference between a surgical incision and, for example, and an accidental cut. The problem is, that your body doesn't understand this difference. In fact, your body reacts pretty dramatically to anything it perceives to be a threat to your well-being. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Without anesthesia, a surgical incision would cause not only pain, but an increase in heart rate, changes in blood pressure and a whole host of other reflexive defense mechanisms which our bodies rely on for protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; So it's important to realize that anesthesia is meant to calm and relax the mind and body in a general sense - not only to block pain but to control those natural defenses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; It's for that reason that the anesthesia you receive will probably include a sedative - either to relax you or to put you to sleep altogether. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Today, surgeons and anesthesiologists have a wide range of options for keeping you comfortable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Pain is an alarm signal sensed by nerves and sent to the brain where it's interpreted and felt. All types of anesthesia work by interfering with the transmission or interpretation of that signal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- ANA 0  Local (L) Bottom //-->
<botHtml secId="x">Why would your doctor recommend or choose one kind of anesthesia over another? It's a decision based on comfort, precisely where on your body your surgery will take place and your overall physical condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This procedure is usually considered to be a simple operation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In unusual cases, a patient may be given general anesthesia - in other words, you might be put to sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But most often, your doctor will simply administer a local anesthetic ... with one or more injections of an anesthetic drug directly into the tissue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The advantage of this kind anesthetic is that it allows you to remain awake, it has less impact on you and your body than general anesthesia does and you recover from it much more quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you've ever experienced any allergic reaction to anesthesia or to any other substance, be sure to let your surgeon or anesthesiologist know well beforehand. &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- ANA 1  Local and General (L&G) Bottom //-->
<botHtml secId="5">&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Why would your doctor recommend or choose one kind of anesthesia over another? It's a decision based on comfort, precisely where on your body your surgery will take place and your overall physical condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This procedure is usually considered to be a simple operation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In unusual cases, a patient may be given general anesthesia - in other words, you might be put to sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But most often, your doctor will simply administer a local anesthetic ... with one or more injections of an anesthetic drug directly into the tissue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The advantage of this kind anesthetic is that it allows you to remain awake, it has less impact on you and your body than general anesthesia does and you recover from it much more quickly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you've ever experienced any allergic reaction to anesthesia or to any other substance, be sure to let your surgeon or anesthesiologist know well beforehand. &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- ANA 2  Local and General and Spinal (L&G&S) Middle //-->
<midHtml secId="x" spotId="x">&lt;p&gt; Why would your doctor recommend or choose one kind of anesthesia over another? It's a decision based on comfort, precisely where on your body your surgery will take place and your overall physical condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This particular surgical technique offers the surgeon a wide selection of anesthesia options. The particular anesthesia chosen will depend on personal preference -- both yours and your doctor's. In some cases, patients are given general anesthesia -- in other words, you might be put to sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But most often, your doctor and anesthesiologist will administer a local anesthetic, either by injecting an anesthetic drug directly around the operative field so that all the tissue layers are numb &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</midHtml>

<botHtml secId="x">&lt;p&gt; A spinal is still considered to be a kind of local anesthesia in that you remain awake during surgery. It's extremely effective, but takes a little longer to wear off than does a more localized anesthesia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Whatever method of pain relief is chosen, the anesthesia will probably be accompanied by a calming intravenous sedative as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you've ever experienced any allergic reaction to anesthesia or to any other substance, be sure to let your surgeon or anesthesiologist know well beforehand. &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- ANA 3  General (G) Bottom //-->
<botHtml secId="x">&lt;p&gt; Why would your doctor recommend or choose one kind of anesthesia over another? It's a decision based on comfort, precisely where on your body your surgery will take place and your overall physical condition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This particular surgical technique offers the surgeon a wide selection of anesthesia options. The particular anesthesia chosen will depend on personal preference - both yours and your doctor's. In some cases, patients are given general anesthesia - in other words, you might be put to sleep. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; But most often, your doctor and anesthesiologist will administer a local anesthetic, either by injecting an anesthetic drug directly around the operative field so that all the tissue layers are numb &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>




<procedureInfo secId="5" spotId="1" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-01b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-01.gif">What we call local anesthesia blocks the signal locally at the nerve where it begins - or somewhere along the nerve between the surgical field and the brain.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="5" spotId="2" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-02b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-02.gif">With local anesthesia, a region of your body is numbed - and you may receive a sedative - but usually, you remain awake.</procedureInfo>

<procedureInfo secId="5" spotId="3" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-03b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-03.gif">If you're given general anesthesia that means that the brain's overall ability to interpret and remember pain has been interrupted.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="5" spotId="4" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-04b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-04.gif">For you, that means being asleep.</procedureInfo>

<procedureInfo secId="x" spotId="x" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-05b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-05.gif">- or by injecting an anesthetic drug into the lower spine. This is called a spinal.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="x" spotId="x" slideimage="/000/preop/000-5-06b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-5-06.gif">It's more generalized in that it numbs the entire lower body. With a spinal, you won't even feel your toes.</procedureInfo>





<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (6) BEFORE SURGERY //-->

<audioImage secId="6" image="/000/preop/host_audio6.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_6before1.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_6before1.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio6.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_6before2.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_6before2.wma"/>
<audioImage secId="x" image="/000/preop/host_audio6.gif" audioMapQT="/000/audio_6before3.mov"  audioMapWM="/000/audio_6before3.wma"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->


<!-- before1 - outpatient //-->

<topHtml secId="6" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;B&lt;/B&gt;ecause you've been scheduled for ambulatory - or outpatient surgery - you're responsible for taking certain precautions before you arrive. Specifically...
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; You must not have anything to eat or drink after midnight on the night before you arrive at the hospital. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Do not take any aspirin or other anti-inflammatory for 10 days before surgery. Occasionally these drugs can interfere with the blood's ability to clot and can actually increase the amount of bleeding during and after surgery. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; If you're on any medication - including over the counter drugs - be sure to ask your doctor whether or not you can continue taking that medication. And if not, how far in advance of surgery you must stop. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Finally, you must also arrange for transportation to and from the place at which the procedure will be performed. Everyone reacts differently to even simple surgical procedures and there's no way you can predict how you'll be feeling after the procedure. So don't forget, following surgery, you will not be allowed to drive. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The nurse and anesthesiologist will be closely monitoring your comfort and progress. Remember, don't hesitate to ask any questions about any of the information that they've just provided. &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<!-- before2 - inpatient //-->

<topHtml secId="x" spotId="x">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;B&lt;/B&gt;ecause you've been scheduled for admission to the hospital for inpatient surgery on the day of surgery, you're responsible for taking certain precautions before you arrive. Specifically...
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; You must not have anything to eat or drink after midnight on the night before you arrive at the hospital. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Do not take any aspirin or other anti-inflammatory for 10 days before surgery. Occasionally these drugs can interfere with the blood's ability to clot and can actually increase the amount of bleeding during and after surgery. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; If you're on any medication - including over the counter drugs - be sure to ask your doctor whether or not you can continue taking that medication. And if not, how far in advance of surgery you must stop. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Finally, you must be prepared to spend one or more nights in the hospital. That means bringing a bag packed with the kind of essential clothing and toiletries you feel you'll need for a period of bed rest. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; It's important that you not make any plans for activities in the days following surgery. After your time in the hospital, you will spend even more time recovering at home. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; And it's impossible to predict with 100% certainty how long you'll be in the hospital or how long you'll have to take it easy at home. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Everyone reacts differently to even simple surgical procedures and there's no way you can predict how you'll be feeling after the procedure. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The nurse and anesthesiologist will be closely monitoring your comfort and progress. Remember, don't hesitate to ask any questions about any of the information that they've just provided. &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<!-- before3 - asprin //-->

<topHtml secId="x" spotId="x">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;B&lt;/B&gt;ecause you've been scheduled for ambulatory - or outpatient surgery - you're responsible for taking certain precautions before you arrive. Specifically...
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; You must not have anything to eat or drink after midnight on the night before you arrive at the hospital. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; If you're on any medication - including over the counter drugs - be sure to ask your doctor whether or not you can continue taking that medication. And if not, how far in advance of surgery you must stop. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;B&gt; &lt;li class="medred"&gt; Finally, you must also arrange for transportation to and from the place at which the procedure will be performed. Everyone reacts differently to even simple surgical procedures and there's no way you can predict how you'll be feeling after the procedure. So don't forget, following surgery, you will not be allowed to drive. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/B&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The nurse and anesthesiologist will be closely monitoring your comfort and progress. Remember, don't hesitate to ask any questions about any of the information that they've just provided. &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>




<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (7) YOUR PROCEDURE //-->

<audioImage secId="7" image="/000/preop/host_audio7.gif" audioMapQT="/332/audio_7proced_332.mov"  audioMapWM="/332/audio_7proced_332.wma"/>

<videoImage secId="7" spotId="1" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_7proced1_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_7proced1_332.wmv"/>
<videoImage secId="7" spotId="7" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_7proced2_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_7proced2_332.wmv"/>
<videoImage secId="7" spotId="10" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/332/video_7proced3_332.mov" videoMapWM="/332/video_7proced3_332.wmv"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->



<topHtml secId="7" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;N&lt;/B&gt;ow it's time to talk about the actual procedure your doctor has recommended for you.
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<botHtml secId="x"></botHtml>

<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="1" slideimage="/332/332-7-01b.gif" image="/332/332-7-01.gif">On the day of your operation, you will be asked to put on a surgical gown.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="2" slideimage="/332/332-7-02b.gif" image="/332/332-7-02.gif">You may receive a sedative by mouth ...</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="3" slideimage="/332/332-7-03b.gif" image="/332/332-7-03.gif">... and an intravenous line may be put in.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="4" slideimage="/332/332-7-04b.gif" image="/332/332-7-04.gif">You will then be transferred to an operating table.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="5" slideimage="/332/332-7-05b.gif" image="/332/332-7-05.gif">Your doctor will scrub thoroughly and will apply an antiseptic solution to the skin around the area where the incision will be made.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="6" slideimage="/332/332-7-06b.gif" image="/332/332-7-06.gif">Then, the doctor will place a sterile drape or towels around the operative site</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="7" slideimage="/332/332-7-07b.gif" image="/332/332-7-07.gif">and will inject a local anesthetic. This will sting a bit, but your breast will quickly begin to feel numb. Usually, the surgeon will inject more than one spot - in order to make sure that the entire area is thoroughly numb.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="8" slideimage="/332/332-7-08b.gif" image="/332/332-7-08.gif">After allowing a few minutes for the anesthetic to take effect, the surgeon will make a small incision.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="9" slideimage="/332/332-7-09b.gif" image="/332/332-7-09.gif">Once the incision has been made, your doctor will begin looking for the lump that is to be removed.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="10" slideimage="/332/332-7-10b.gif" image="/332/332-7-10.gif">You will feel some pressure or even slight tugging or pulling - but you should not feel any sharp pain. If you do begin to feel pain, you should tell the doctor and you will be given more anesthetic.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="11" slideimage="/332/332-7-11b.gif" image="/332/332-7-11.gif">Once the lump is removed, the doctor will close the skin over the incision as neatly and as cosmetically as they are able.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="12" slideimage="/332/332-7-12b.gif" image="/332/332-7-12.gif">Finally, a sterile dressing is applied.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="7" spotId="13" slideimage="/332/332-7-13b.gif" image="/332/332-7-13.gif">Your specimen will be sent immediately to a lab for microscopic analysis. Your doctor will tell you when to expect result from those tests.</procedureInfo>




<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->

<!-- (8) YOUR RECOVERY //-->

<audioImage secId="8" image="/000/preop/host_audio8.gif" audioMapQT="/332/audio_8recov_332.mov"  audioMapWM="/332/audio_8recov_332.wma"/>

<videoImage secId="8" spotId="1" image="/000/icon_movie_new.gif" videoMapQT="/000/video_8recov1.mov" videoMapWM="/000/video_8recov1.wmv"/>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->



<!-- recov 1 - outpatient //-->

<topHtml secId="8" spotId="1">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;F&lt;/B&gt;ollowing the procedure, you'll be moved then to a recovery area where you can relax until the sedation and anesthetic has worn off - and until the doctor is satisfied that you are fit to go home. Plan on spending several hours in recovery. Your doctor may be able to give you a more precise estimate prior to surgery.
&lt;p&gt; Before you leave, you'll probably be prescribed a pain killer along with any other medication your doctor feels you need to take. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<!-- recov 2 - inpatient //-->

<topHtml secId="x" spotId="x">&lt;B class="largeviolet"&gt;F&lt;/B&gt;ollowing the procedure, you'll be moved then to a recovery area where you can relax until the sedation and anesthetic has worn off - At some point you will be moved to your room. While you're in the hospital, doctors and nurses will regularly check you - monitoring your progress following surgery.
&lt;p&gt; It's important that you realize your time in the hospital is an extension of the surgical procedure.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; While you're in the hospital, your medical team will continue to monitor your body's immediate reaction to the procedure just performed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; That means that your time in the hospital is not really for rest and recovery. And you should expect to have your movements restricted and even your sleep interrupted by nurses or other medical staff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The amount of time that you spend in the hospital will depend on your age, your health and whether or not any complications arise. Be assured that once your doctor feels that your condition is properly stabilized, you'll be allowed to leave. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Be sure to follow your doctor's advice and allow the full-recommended period of time before you return to your normal routine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</topHtml>

<!-- iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiii //-->


<midHtml secId="8" spotId="12">&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; If you experience any of these symptoms or excessive discomfort, call your doctor immediately. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This kind of bleeding becomes increasingly unlikely more than 24 hours after surgery - although a sharp impact to the biopsy site could trigger bleeding even days after surgery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Once you return home, you will be responsible to keeping the dressing intact and clean. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; As with all surgery, you should be alert for signs of infection near the incision - increased swelling, redness, bleeding or other discharge. Your doctor may advise you to be on the alert for other symptoms as well. If you experience any unusual symptoms, report them to your doctor right away. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; You may also notice some bruising in the general area of the incision. The discoloration may be extensive - but as with any bruise, it should heal on it's own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Before you leave, you'll be given discharge guidelines which may include diet, medication, work and other activity restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;</midHtml>

<botHtml secId="8">&lt;p&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This program has been designed to help you to understand a surgical procedure and to empower you to be an active participant in your own care. We hope that you take the time to discuss alternative treatments with your doctor and that you learn as much as you can about your own particular medical situation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; We also want to make sure that you understand all the risks of surgery and potential complications which can follow - no matter how unlikely they may be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; It's important that you understand exactly what the procedure entails - including the risks, benefits and alternative treatments - before you decide to proceed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Always remember that the final decision to go ahead or not is up to you. &lt;/p&gt;</botHtml>


<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="1" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-01b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-01.gif">Most patients experience at least some pain following surgery, but if properly handled, it shouldn't present any serious problems.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="2" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-02b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-02.gif">Pain used to be regarded as an unavoidable side effect of surgery, but today pain can be managed with great effectiveness.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="3" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-03b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-03.gif">And as the patient, you have an important role to play.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="4" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-04b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-04.gif">Before surgery, be sure to ask the medical staff about the type and duration of pain normally associated with your surgery.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="5" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-05b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-05.gif">Find out, in advance, about your pain management options. Work with the staff to develop a pain management plan. Discuss your options. There are alternatives to drugs that can lessen your need for pain medication.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="6" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-06b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-06.gif">Ask your doctor for help finding a pain management class. Many of these workshops teach helpful relaxation techniques, positive thinking and nerve stimulation exercises.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="7" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-07b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-07.gif">Following surgery, make sure to let your nurse know right away how you're feeling and whether or not you are in any pain. Be specific, and help them to measure your discomfort.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="8" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-08b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-08.gif">If you're having trouble expressing yourself, try to rank what you're feeling on a scale from 1 to 10.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="9" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-09b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-09.gif">Never be shy about asking for help. If you experience pain that just won't go away, report it to the nurse.</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="10" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-10b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-10.gif">Pain is an important indicator that helps you and your medical staff understand your body's healing process...</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="11" slideimage="/332/332-8-11b.gif" image="/332/332-8-11.gif">Breast biopsy surgery only rarely leads to complications. One significant risk is bleeding.
&lt;p&gt; Sometimes bleeding can begin inside the breast, in the area where tissue was removed. Symptoms of this kind of bleeding include pain and or swelling or firmness within the breast. &lt;/p&gt;</procedureInfo>
<procedureInfo secId="8" spotId="12" slideimage="/000/preop/000-8-00b.gif" image="/000/preop/000-8-00.gif">You'll also make at least one follow-up appointment so that the doctor will be able to check the healing of the incision and/or to remove sutures.</procedureInfo>



</preopData>
