<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<preopData>
<helpElement pagename="editPartner.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing Partners&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This page is used to add, update and delete partner information.  While creating partners you have many options to choose from to customize the partners interface.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To add a new partner go to the partners drop down and select 'Create New'. Enter all of the options you want the partner to have access to and click 'insert'. This next step while creating a partner is to edit the navigation, centers, procedures and special instructions for the partner.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To edit a partner simply update the partners information and click the 'update' button.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete a partner simply click the 'delete' button. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; To finalize your edits and publish new XML to the server click 'Generate XML'.  This process will create a new file called /xml/partners/[partnerId].xml.
</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editPartnerBar.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing A Partners Navigation Bar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt; This screen will allow you to add, update and delete options from a partners top navigation bar. Note: The options available for navigational elements are created in the 'Navigation' section of the administration tool. If you wish to create new options not defined in the current list boxes you would create them there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To create a new top navigation element, go to the new element area and enter the sequence and navigation option. Then press the insert button.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To edit a top navigation element press 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete an element click 'delete'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Note: to add a navigation drop down find the element you wish to add to and click 'Edit Drop Downs'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes here you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect.</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editPartnerDrop.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing A Partners Navigation Drop Downs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This screen will allow you to add, update and delete options from a partners top navigation bars drop down menu. Note: The options available for navigational drop downs are created in the 'Navigation' section of the administration tool.  If you wish to create new options not defined in the current list boxes you would create them there.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To create a new drop down, go to the new drop down area and enter the sequence and Navigation Drop Down ID. Then press the insert button.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To edit a top drop down press 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete an drop down click 'delete'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes here you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect.</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editPartnerCenters.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing a Partners Centers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This screen is used to give a partner access to MedSelfEd Centers.  To associate a center to a partner simply click on the centers checkbox and press 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes here you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect.</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editPartnerProds.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing a Partners Procedures&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This screen is used to give a partner access to MedSelfEd Procedures.  To associate a procedures to a partner simply click on the procedures checkbox and press 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes here you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect.</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editSpecailInstr.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing a Partners Special Instructions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This screen is used to add, update and delete special instructions from a partners website. To add special instruction you should choose what procedure you'd like it show up on, type the new text and click 'insert'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To update instruction click 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete press 'delete'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes here you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect. </helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editDiscliamer.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing a Partners Discliamer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This screen is used to update a discliamer on a partners website. To edit the discliamer you should enter the text in the text area above and click 'update'.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;After you have made your changes you will need to go back to the 'Partners' screen and click 'Generate XML' for your changes to take affect. </helpElement>

<helpElement pagename="editNavigation.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing available MedSelfEd Navigation Elements&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editCenters.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing MedSelfEd Centers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editCentersProds.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Adding Procedures to MedSelfEd Centers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editProds.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing MedSelfEd Procedures&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editQuestions.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing Questions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This page is used to create new questions to be displayed on procedure pages. Your options are to add, update, edit and delete questions. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To add a new question you must first go to the 'Questions' drop down and select 'Create new'. Then select what procedure you would like the question to show up on. If you want the question to show up all the procedures select 'all'.  Next type the question in the text box below.  Once you have created  question click the insert button and you will return to the questions list. The next step is to add answers to the question. To do this click 'Edit Answers' on the question you wish to update.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To edit a question simply update the procedure or test and click the 'update button.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete a question simply click the 'delete' button</helpElement>
<helpElement pagename="editAnswers.asp">&lt;b class=medred&gt; Editing Answers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;This page is used to update, add or delete the options given for each question.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To add new choice scroll to the bottom of the page and select enter the text of the choice and if it is correct. Note: If the question is in a survey format you are allowed to choose 'Yes' because all survey questions are considered correct.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To edit a answer simply update the text and click the 'update button.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;To delete a answer simply click the 'delete' button</helpElement>
</preopData>
